<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research &amp; more... on Research &amp; more...</title>
    <link>https://TristanSalles.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research &amp; more... on Research &amp; more...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Tristan Salles</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Australian landscape evolution since the Late Jurassic</title>
      <link>https://TristanSalles.github.io/talk/ifp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TristanSalles.github.io/talk/ifp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>150 Million years of landscape evolution of eastern Australian continent</title>
      <link>https://TristanSalles.github.io/talk/egu17_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TristanSalles.github.io/talk/egu17_1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influence of dynamic topography on landscape evolution and passive continental margin stratigraphy</title>
      <link>https://TristanSalles.github.io/talk/egu17_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TristanSalles.github.io/talk/egu17_2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responses of reefs to climatic forcing – A numerical perspective</title>
      <link>https://TristanSalles.github.io/talk/coral/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TristanSalles.github.io/talk/coral/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influence of mantle flow on the drainage of eastern Australia since the Jurassic Period</title>
      <link>https://TristanSalles.github.io/publication/au-lem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TristanSalles.github.io/publication/au-lem/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complete list of talks</title>
      <link>https://TristanSalles.github.io/talk/prior17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TristanSalles.github.io/talk/prior17/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;2017&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T. Salles, 2017. Responses of reefs to climatic forcing – A numerical perspective, Centre for Coral Reef Studies, USyd.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T. Salles, N. Flament, D. Muller, P. Rey, 2017. Influence of dynamic topography on the evolution of the Australian landscape since the Late Jurassic, Workshop in High Performance Computing, EAGE IFP Paris. T. Salles, N. Flament, D. Muller, 2017. 150 Million years of landscape evolution of eastern Australian continent, European Geophysical Union General Assembly Vienna, Austria.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X. Ding, T. Salles, N. Flament, P. Rey, 2017. Influence of dynamic topography on landscape evolution and passive continental margin stratigraphy, European Geophysical Union General Assembly Vienna, Austria.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T. Salles, 2016. Regional to continental scale model of Earth surface evolution, Seminar - Granular Forum, USyd.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T. Salles, 2016. Update on Badlands development &amp;amp; applications, Basin Genesis Hub meeting, Melbourne.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X. Ding, T. Salles, N. Flament, P. Rey, 2016. Impact of dynamic topography on stratigraphic evolution, Basin Genesis Hub meeting, Melbourne.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T. Salles, N. Flament, D. Muller, 2016. Influence of dynamic topography on the evolution of the Australian landscape since the Late Jurassic, Australian Earth Science Convention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;V. Bianchi, T. Smith, T. Salles, J. Esterle, 2016. Coupling dynamic topography with Stratigraphic Forward Modelling: case study Springbok Sandstone, Australian Earth Science Convention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;D. Muller, N. Flament, T. Salles, K. Matthews, M. Gurnis, 2016. The eastern Australian record of continental travel, dynamic topography and landscape evolution since Pangaea breakup, Australian Earth Science Convention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T. Salles, 2016. Continental-Scale Landscape Dynamic, University of Bergen, Norway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T. Salles, N. Flament, D. Muller, 2016. Influence of dynamic topography on the evolution of the Australian landscape since the Late Jurassic, American Geophysical Union.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X. Ding, T. Salles, N. Flament, P. Rey, 2016. Modeling passive margins stratigraphy from the in- terplay between sea-level change, thermal subsidence, precipitation and dynamic topography, American Geophysical Union.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;S. Moron, S. Gallagher, L. Moresi, T. Salles, P. Rey, T. Payenberg, 2016. Investigating the effect of plate-mantle interaction in basin creation and associated drainage systems: insights from the North West Shelf of Australia, American Geophysical Union.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;2015&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Müller D, T. Salles, N. Flament, M. Gurnis, 2015. Continental inter-superswell travel and landscape evolution – GeoBerlin, Germany, 2015.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bianchi V., T. Salles, 2015. Stratigraphic Forward Modelling on reservoir geometry of the Springbok Formation (Late Jurassic) – Bowen Basin Symposium and Beyond October 2015 (Brisbane)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Müller D, N. Flament, K. Matthews, S. Williams, M. Gurnis, T. Salles, 2015. How Australian Plate Interaction With Subducting Slabs and the South Pacific Superswell Drove Multi-Phase Uplift and Paleogeography in Eastern Australia – ICE-SEG AAPG, Melbourne, Australia, September 2015.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bianchi V., T. Salles, J. Esterle, 2015. Stratigraphic Forward Modelling for investigating hidden reservoir geometries and connectivity: Springbok Formation – ICE-SEG AAPG, Melbourne, Australia, September 2015.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flament N., T. Salles, R.D. Müller, M. Gurnis, 2015. Influence of subduction history and surface processes on continental-scale topography – XIV International Workshop on Modelling of Mantle and Lithosphere Dynamics, Ausgust 2015 (France)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bianchi V., J. Esterle, T. Salles, 2015. Stratigraphic Forward Modelling on reservoir geometry of the Springbok Formation (Middle Jurassic): prediction on the unexplored depocenter of Surat Basin (QLD, Australia) – IAS June 2015 Krakow (Poland)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bianchi V., T. Salles, 2015. Hidden geometry in Surat Basin depocenter: Springbok Formation – AAPG Geosciences Technology Workshop (GTW) entitled: Opportunities and Advancements in Coal Bed Methane in the Asia Pacific - January 2015 (Brisbane)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;2014&#34;&gt;2014&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Müller D, P. Rey, L. Moresi, L. Mondy, G. Duclaux, T. Salles, T. Rawling, C. Elders, 2014. Next generation modelling of rift basins and continental margins – Australian Earth Science Convention, Newcastle, Australia, July 2014.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mondy L., P. Rey, G. Duclaux, T. Salles, L. Moresi, 2014. A digital workbench for understanding the stratigraphic evolution of rift basins and continental margins – Australian Earth Science Convention, Newcastle, Australia, July 2014.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upton, P., G. Duclaux, D. Craw, T. Salles, 2013. Reconstructing the formation and in-filling of Lake Manuherikia, Otago: Linking geodynamics and surface processes – AGU Fall meeting 2013, San Francisco, USA, December 2013.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mondy L., Duclaux G., Salles T., Thomas C., Rey P., 2013. Modelling stratigraphic and surface dynamics processes on a coupled thermo-mechanical lithospheric model: an example in oblique continental rifting. IAG Paris.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bianchi, V., T. Salles, G. Duclaux, M. Ghinassi, 2013. Reconstruction of a syn-depositional cross-valley faulting through numerical modelling: the Plio-Pleistocene Ambra paleovalley (North Apennines, Italy) – GeoSed, Roma, Italy, September 2013.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bianchi V., Salles T., Duclaux G.„ Ghinassi M., 2013. Evolution of syn-depositional cross-valley faulting: numerical reconstruction of the Plio-Pleistocene Ambra paleovalley (Northern Apennines, Italy). IAS, Manchester, UK, September 2013..&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mondy L., Duclaux G., Salles T., Thomas C., Rey P., 2013. Stratigraphic Modelling of Continental Rifting. EGU 2013, Vienna, Austria, May 2013.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bourget J., Salles T., Ainsworth B., Duclaux G., 2013. Quantifying the importance of sediment supply, global eustasy and fault-induced accommodation in controlling delta architecture, shelf-margin growth and deep-water sediment transfer: insights from stratigraphic-forward modelling in northern Australia.. AAPG Annual Convention Denver.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duclaux G., Salles T., 2013. Four-Dimensional Detrital Iron Ore Deposit Exploration Using Surface Processes Modelling - Hamersley Province Example.. Iron Ore conference Perth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;2012&#34;&gt;2012&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salles T., Duclaux G., 2012. 3D stratigraphic and geomorphic modelling from source to sink, 34th IGC, Brisbane.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duclaux G., Salles T., 2012. Placer deposits: where should we look next? Surface Processes Modelling applied to mineral exploration, 34th IGC, Brisbane.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salles T., Duclaux G., 2012. Next generation of 3D stratigraphic and geomorphic modelling, EGU, Vienna.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salles T., Duclaux G., Mansour J., Rey P., Moresi L., 2012. Testing basin-scale evolution concepts on a supercomputer at realistic tectonic and sedimentary rates, EGU, Vienna.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Miranda J., Eid R., McLean M., Griffiths C., Dyt C., Salles T., O’Brien G., Tingate P., Divko L. G., Campi M., 2012. Gippsland basin stratigraphic and CO2 migration modelling: workflows for building regional, geological carbon storage (GCS) reservoir models, Eastern Australian Basins Symposium IV, Brisbane.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Griffiths C., Dyt C., Huang X., Salles T., 2012. Multiscalar Forward modelling of carbonate heterogeneity, AAPG/SPE/SEG Hedberg Conference France.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;2011&#34;&gt;2011&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duclaux, G., Salles T., Rey P., 2011. Numerical modelling of tectonic and surface processes: insights into continental rifting and the formation of passive margins, GSA Annual Meeting 2011, Minneapolis, USA, October 2011.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salles T., Duclaux G., 2011. Tellus: A new HPC model based on particle-in-cell technique to investigate stratigraphy evolution, GSA Annual Meeting 2011, Minneapolis, USA, October 2011.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Griffiths C., Dyt C., Huang X., Salles T., Corbel S., 2011. Predicting Rock Properties away from data in Aquifer-hosted Geothermal Projects, West Australian Geothermal Energy Symposium, Perth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;2010&#34;&gt;2010&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salles T., Duclaux G., 2010. SedSim model challenges and developments apply to Ore Deposits R&amp;amp;D, IFP Paris, 2010.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salles T., McGee D., Griffiths C., Ryer M. S., 2010. SedSim modelling of controls on confined mini basin fill by eustatic and halokinetic mechanisms (Gulf of Mexico), symposium ASF, RST 2010.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;2009&#34;&gt;2009&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salles T., Griffiths C., Dyt C., 2009. Aeolian sediment transport integration in general stratigraphic forward modelling. IAMG Conference, Stanford.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Griffiths C., Dyt C., Salles T., 2009. The 2009 Status of SedSim modelling and future plans. IAMG Conference, Stanford.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Griffiths C., Salles T., Li F., Dyt C., 2009. Using SedSim to predict the response of coastal sediments to climate change in Australia. Climate Change: The environmental and socio-economic response in the southern Baltic region. Poland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salles T., 2009. Climate change impact on seabed sediment transport in the Australian exclusive economic zone. Society of Underwater Technology Annual Conference, Perth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;2008&#34;&gt;2008&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salles T., Li F., Griffiths C. M., Dyt C. P., Feng M., Jenkins C., 2008. Climate change impact on seabed sediment transport in the Australian Exclusive Economic Zone. Coast to Coast Conference, Darwin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salles T., Li F., Griffiths C. M., 2008. Climate change impact on seabed sediment transport all around Australian. ANZIAM Conference Perth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eschard R., Teles V., Salles T., Lopez S., 2008. Simulation of the stratigraphic architecture of the PAB turbiditic channels: the additional value of a process-based numerical approach with the CATS model. AAPG, San Antonio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teles V., Eschard R., Lopez S., Salles T., 2008. A Process-based Cellular Automata Model for Turbiditic Reservoirs (CATS) Applied to Complex Turbiditic Systems. AAPG, San Antonio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;2007&#34;&gt;2007&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salles T., Lopez S., Cacas M.C., Eschard R., Euzen T. , Teles V., Mulder, T., 2007. Cellular Automata Modelling of Turbidity Currents Deposits. AAPG Annual Convention Exhibition, Long Beach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salles T., Mulder T., Gaudin M., Lopez S., Cacas M.C., Cirac P., 2007. Simulating the 1999 turbidity current in Capbreton canyon (French Atlantic Coast) using a Cellular Automata model. EGU Vienna.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;2006&#34;&gt;2006&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salles T., Lopez S., Euzen T., Eschard R., 2006. Integrating basin-scale forcing parameters in density currents process-based modelling. External Controls on Deep Water Depositional Systems; Climate, Sea-Level and Sediment Flux, London.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Granjeon D., Wolf S., Lopez S., Salles T., 2006. 3D Stratigraphic Modelling in Complex Tectonics Area at an Exploration to Reservoir Scale. AAPG Annual Convention, Houston.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salles T., Lopez S., Cacas M.C., Granjeon D., Mulder T., 2006. Geological Modelling Using Cellular Automata. AAPG Annual Convention, Houston.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;2005&#34;&gt;2005&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salles T., Cacas M.C., Mulder T., 2005. Modélisation numérique du remplissage sédimentaire des canyons et chenaux sous-marins par Approche Génétique. Congrés ASF (Giens), France.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mulder T., Callec Y., Joseph P., Robin C., Schneider J.L., Salles T., Allard J., Ferger B., Bonnel C., Cremer M., Ducassou E., Dujoncquoy E., Gaudin M., Hanquiez V., Marchés E., Parize O., Toucanne S., Zaragosi S., 2005. Les dépots de lobes turbiditiques du lac du Lauzanier (Ubaye, France). Congrés ASF (Giens), France.
Salles T., Cacas M.C., Mulder T., 2005. Simulating Turbidity Currents through a Cellular Automata Model. AAPG International Conference, Paris.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;2004&#34;&gt;2004&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salles T., Cacas M.C., Mulder T., 2004. Cellular automata approach for simulated gravity flows. Modelling of Turbidity Currents and Related Gravity Currents Workshop, Santa Barbara.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Badlands: A parallel basin and landscape dynamics model</title>
      <link>https://TristanSalles.github.io/publication/softx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TristanSalles.github.io/publication/softx/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>External Project</title>
      <link>https://TristanSalles.github.io/project/example-external-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TristanSalles.github.io/project/example-external-project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with the Academic framework for Hugo</title>
      <link>https://TristanSalles.github.io/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TristanSalles.github.io/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The Academic framework enables you to easily create a beautifully simple personal or academic website using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; static site generator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easily manage your homepage, blog posts, publications, talks, and projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configurable widgets available for Biography, Publications, Projects, News/Blog, Talks, and Contact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Need a different section? Just use the Custom widget!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write in &lt;a href=&#34;https://TristanSalles.github.io/post/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; for easy formatting and code highlighting, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/LaTeX/Mathematics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt; for mathematical expressions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social/academic network linking, &lt;a href=&#34;https://analytics.google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt; comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsive and mobile friendly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple and refreshing one page design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to customize&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com/create-your-website-with-hugo/#installing-hugo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Install Hugo&lt;/a&gt; and create a new website by typing the following commands in your &lt;em&gt;Terminal&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Command Prompt&lt;/em&gt; app:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new site my_website
cd my_website
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Install Academic with &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/articles/set-up-git/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;git&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic.git themes/academic
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or alternatively, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/archive/master.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;download Academic&lt;/a&gt; and extract it into a &lt;code&gt;themes/academic&lt;/code&gt; folder within your Hugo website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are creating a new website, copy the contents of the &lt;code&gt;exampleSite&lt;/code&gt; folder to your website root folder, overwriting existing files if necessary. The &lt;code&gt;exampleSite&lt;/code&gt; folder contains an example config file and content to help you get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cp -av themes/academic/exampleSite/* .
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Start the Hugo server from your website root folder:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo server --watch
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;localhost:1313&lt;/a&gt; and your new Academic powered website should appear.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Customize your website - refer to the &lt;em&gt;Getting Started&lt;/em&gt; section below&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Build your site by running the &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; command. Then &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com/create-your-website-with-hugo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;host it for free using Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;. Or alternatively, copy the generated &lt;code&gt;public/&lt;/code&gt; directory (by FTP, Rsync, etc.) to your production web server (such as your university&amp;rsquo;s hosting service).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming you created a new website with the example content following the installation steps above, this section explores just a few more steps in order to customize it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;core-parameters&#34;&gt;Core parameters&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core parameters for the website can be edited in the &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; configuration file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set &lt;code&gt;baseurl&lt;/code&gt; to your website URL (we recommend &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com/create-your-website-with-hugo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; for free hosting)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set &lt;code&gt;title&lt;/code&gt; to your desired website title such as your name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The example Disqus commenting variable should be cleared (e.g. &lt;code&gt;disqusShortname = &amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;) or set to your own &lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt; shortname to enable commenting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit your details under &lt;code&gt;[params]&lt;/code&gt;; these will be displayed mainly in the homepage &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;contact&lt;/em&gt; widgets (if used). To disable a contact field, simply clear the value to &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Place a square cropped portrait photo named &lt;code&gt;portrait.jpg&lt;/code&gt; into the &lt;code&gt;static/img/&lt;/code&gt; folder, overwriting any defaults. Alternatively, you can edit the &lt;code&gt;avatar&lt;/code&gt; filepath to point to a different image name or clear the value to disable the avatar feature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To enable LaTeX math for your site, set &lt;code&gt;math = true&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social/academic networking links are defined as multiples of &lt;code&gt;[[params.social]]&lt;/code&gt;. They can be created or deleted as necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduce-yourself&#34;&gt;Introduce yourself&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edit your biography in the &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; widget &lt;code&gt;content/home/about.md&lt;/code&gt; that you copied across from the &lt;code&gt;themes/academic/exampleSite/&lt;/code&gt; folder. The research interests and qualifications are stored as &lt;code&gt;interests&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;education&lt;/code&gt; variables. The academic qualifications are defined as multiples of &lt;code&gt;[[education.courses]]&lt;/code&gt; and can be created or deleted as necessary. It&amp;rsquo;s possible to completely hide the interests and education lists by deleting their respective variables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;customize-the-homepage&#34;&gt;Customize the homepage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refer to our guide on using &lt;a href=&#34;https://TristanSalles.github.io/post/widgets/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;widgets&lt;/a&gt; to customize your homepage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;add-your-content&#34;&gt;Add your content&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refer to our guide on &lt;a href=&#34;https://TristanSalles.github.io/post/managing-content/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;managing content&lt;/a&gt; to create your own publications, blog posts, talks, and projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;remove-unused-widgets-and-pages&#34;&gt;Remove unused widgets and pages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://TristanSalles.github.io/post/managing-content/#removing-content&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How to remove unused widgets and content pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;customization-upgrading&#34;&gt;Customization &amp;amp; Upgrading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continue reading below for advanced customization tips and instructions for keeping the framework up-to-date with any improvements that become available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;advanced-customization&#34;&gt;Advanced customization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is possible to carry out many customizations without touching any files in &lt;code&gt;themes/academic&lt;/code&gt;, making it easier to upgrade the framework in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;navigation-menu&#34;&gt;Navigation menu&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;[[menu.main]]&lt;/code&gt; entries towards the bottom of &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; define the navigation links at the top of the website. They can be added or removed as desired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create a dropdown sub-menu, add &lt;code&gt;identifier = &amp;quot;something&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; to the parent item and &lt;code&gt;parent = &amp;quot;something&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; to the child item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;website-icon&#34;&gt;Website icon&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save your main icon and mobile icon as square PNG images named &lt;code&gt;icon.png&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;apple-touch-icon.png&lt;/code&gt;, respectively. Place them in your root &lt;code&gt;static/img/&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;theme-color-css&#34;&gt;Theme color (CSS)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can link custom CSS assets (relative to your root &lt;code&gt;static/css&lt;/code&gt;) from your &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; using &lt;code&gt;custom_css = [&amp;quot;custom.css&amp;quot;]&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, lets make a green theme. First, define &lt;code&gt;custom_css = [&amp;quot;green.css&amp;quot;]&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt;. Then we can download the example &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/gcushen/d5525a4506b9ccf83f2bce592a895495&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;green theme&lt;/a&gt; and save it as &lt;code&gt;static/css/green.css&lt;/code&gt;, relative to your website root (i.e. &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; in the &lt;code&gt;themes&lt;/code&gt; directory).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;analytics&#34;&gt;Analytics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To enable &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/analytics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, add your tracking code in &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; similarly to &lt;code&gt;googleAnalytics = &amp;quot;UA-12345678-9&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;third-party-and-local-scripts-js&#34;&gt;Third party and local scripts (JS)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add a third party script, create a file named &lt;code&gt;head_custom.html&lt;/code&gt; in a &lt;code&gt;layouts/partials/&lt;/code&gt; folder at the root of your website (not in the &lt;code&gt;themes&lt;/code&gt; folder). Any HTML code added to this file will be included within your website&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. Therefore, it&amp;rsquo;s suitable for adding custom metadata or third party scripts specified with the &lt;em&gt;async&lt;/em&gt; attribute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whereas for your own local scripts, you can link your local JS assets (relative to your root &lt;code&gt;static/js&lt;/code&gt;) from your &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; using &lt;code&gt;custom_js  = [&amp;quot;custom.js&amp;quot;]&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;language-and-translation&#34;&gt;Language and translation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interface text (e.g. buttons) is stored in language files which are collected from Academic&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;themes/academic/i18n/&lt;/code&gt; folder, as well as an &lt;code&gt;i18n/&lt;/code&gt; folder at the root of your project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To edit the interface text, copy &lt;code&gt;themes/academic/i18n/en.yaml&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;i18n/en.yaml&lt;/code&gt; (relative to the root of your website). Open the new file and make any desired changes to the text appearing after &lt;code&gt;translation:&lt;/code&gt;. Note that the language files are formatted in YAML syntax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To translate the interface text to another language, follow the above instructions, but name the new file in the form &lt;code&gt;i18n/X.yaml&lt;/code&gt; where &lt;code&gt;X&lt;/code&gt; is the appropriate &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/tags/ref_language_codes.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ISO/RFC5646 language identifier&lt;/a&gt; for the translation. Then follow the brief instructions in the &lt;em&gt;Language&lt;/em&gt; section at the bottom of your &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt;. To change the default language used by Academic, set &lt;code&gt;defaultContentLanguage&lt;/code&gt; to the desired language identifier in your configuration file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To translate the navigation bar, you can edit the default &lt;code&gt;[[menu.main]]&lt;/code&gt; instances in &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt;. However, for a multilingual site, you will need to duplicate all of the &lt;code&gt;[[menu.main]]&lt;/code&gt; instances and rename the new instances from &lt;code&gt;[[menu.main]]&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;[[languages.X.menu.main]]&lt;/code&gt;, where &lt;code&gt;X&lt;/code&gt; is the language identifier (e.g. &lt;code&gt;[[languages.zh.menu.main]]&lt;/code&gt; for Simplified Chinese). Thus, the navigation bar can be displayed in multiple languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To translate a content file in your &lt;code&gt;content/&lt;/code&gt; folder into another language, copy the file to &lt;code&gt;filename.X.md&lt;/code&gt; where &lt;code&gt;filename&lt;/code&gt; is your existing filename and &lt;code&gt;X&lt;/code&gt; is the appropriate &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/tags/ref_language_codes.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ISO/RFC5646 language identifier&lt;/a&gt; for the translation. Then translate the content in the new file to the specified language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For further details on Hugo&amp;rsquo;s internationalization and multilingual features, refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content/multilingual/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;associated Hugo documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;permalinks&#34;&gt;Permalinks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Permalinks&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;permanent links&lt;/em&gt;, are URLs to individual pages and posts on your website. They are permanent web addresses which can be used to link to your content. Using Hugo&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;permalinks&lt;/em&gt; option these can be easily customized. For example, the blog post URL can be changed to the form &lt;em&gt;yourURL/2016/05/01/my-post-slug&lt;/em&gt; by adding the following near the top of your &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; (before &lt;code&gt;[params]&lt;/code&gt; settings):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[permalinks]
    post = &amp;quot;/:year/:month/:day/:slug&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where &lt;code&gt;:slug&lt;/code&gt; defaults to the filename of the post, excluding the file extension. However, slug may be overridden on a per post basis if desired, simply by setting &lt;code&gt;slug = &amp;quot;my-short-post-title&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; in your post preamble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;upgrading&#34;&gt;Upgrading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to &lt;em&gt;star&lt;/em&gt; the project on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; and monitor the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/commits/master&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;commits&lt;/a&gt; for updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before upgrading the framework, it is recommended to make a backup of your entire website directory, or at least your &lt;code&gt;themes/academic&lt;/code&gt; directory. You can also read about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/releases&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;most recent milestones&lt;/a&gt; (but this doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily reflect the latest &lt;em&gt;master&lt;/em&gt; release).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before upgrading for the first time, the remote &lt;em&gt;origin&lt;/em&gt; repository should be renamed to &lt;em&gt;upstream&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd themes/academic
$ git remote rename origin upstream
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To list available updates:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd themes/academic
$ git fetch upstream
$ git log --pretty=oneline --abbrev-commit --decorate HEAD..upstream/master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, upgrade by running:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git pull upstream
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have modified files in &lt;code&gt;themes/academic&lt;/code&gt;, git will attempt to auto-merge changes. If conflicts are reported, you will need to manually edit the files with conflicts and add them back (&lt;code&gt;git add &amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there are any issues after upgrading, you may wish to compare your site with the latest &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/tree/master/exampleSite&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;example site&lt;/a&gt; to check if any settings changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;feedback-contributing&#34;&gt;Feedback &amp;amp; Contributing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt; to let me know about any bugs or feature requests, or alternatively make a pull request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For general questions about Hugo, there is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo discussion forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2016 &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;George Cushen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Released under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/blob/master/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customizing the homepage with widgets</title>
      <link>https://TristanSalles.github.io/post/widgets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TristanSalles.github.io/post/widgets/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Homepage widgets display as sections on the homepage. They can be enabled/disabled and configured as desired. Academic has the following widgets available to use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About/biography&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selected publications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recent publications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recent news/blog posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selected talks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recent talks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom widget (demonstrated with the &lt;em&gt;teaching&lt;/em&gt; example)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The example site that you copied to create your site uses all the different types of widget (except talks), so you can generally just delete the widgets you don&amp;rsquo;t need and customize the parameters of the widgets you wish to keep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The parameters for each widget vary. They can be found in the preamble/frontmatter (between the pair of &lt;code&gt;+++&lt;/code&gt;) for each widget installed in the &lt;code&gt;content/home/&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;By default, publications will be displayed in a simple list. If you prefer a more detailed list with abstract and image, you can enable the detailed publication list on the homepage by setting &lt;code&gt;detailed_list = true&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;content/home/publications.md&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;add-a-widget-to-the-homepage&#34;&gt;Add a widget to the homepage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add a widget manually, copy the relevant widget from &lt;code&gt;themes/academic/exampleSite/content/home/&lt;/code&gt; to your &lt;code&gt;content/home/&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Widget identifiers are set to their respective filenames, so a &lt;code&gt;content/home/about.md&lt;/code&gt; widget can be linked from the navigation bar by setting the relevant URL as &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;#about&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that if you want to use multiple instances of a widget, each widget will be assigned a unique ID based on the filename that you set. You can then use that ID for linking, like in the above example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;using-the-custom-widget&#34;&gt;Using the custom widget&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use the custom widget to create your own home page sections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply duplicate (copy/paste) and rename the example &lt;em&gt;teaching&lt;/em&gt; file at &lt;code&gt;content/home/teaching.md&lt;/code&gt;. Then edit the section title, weight (refer to &lt;em&gt;Ordering sections&lt;/em&gt; below), and content as desired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may also wish to add a navigation link to the top of the page that points to the new section. This can be achieved by adding something similar to the following lines to your &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt;, where the URL will consist of the first title word in lowercase:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[[menu.main]]
    name = &amp;quot;Research&amp;quot;
    url = &amp;quot;#research&amp;quot;
    weight = 10
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;remove-a-widget-from-the-homepage&#34;&gt;Remove a widget from the homepage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not require a particular widget, you can simply delete any associated files from the &lt;code&gt;content/home/&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remove a navigation link from the top of the page, remove the associated &lt;code&gt;[[menu.main]]&lt;/code&gt; entry in &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ordering-widgets&#34;&gt;Ordering widgets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The order that the homepage widgets are displayed in is defined by the &lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt; parameter in each of the files in the &lt;code&gt;content/home/&lt;/code&gt; directory. The widgets are displayed in ascending order of their &lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;, so you can simply edit the &lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt; parameters as desired.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing content</title>
      <link>https://TristanSalles.github.io/post/managing-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TristanSalles.github.io/post/managing-content/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a brief guide to managing content with the Academic framework. Content can include publications, projects, talks, and news/blog articles. After you have read this guide about creating and managing content, you may also be interested to learn about &lt;a href=&#34;https://TristanSalles.github.io/post/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;writing content with Markdown, LaTeX, and Shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To enable LaTeX math rendering for a page, you should include &lt;code&gt;math = true&lt;/code&gt; in the page&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;+++&lt;/code&gt; preamble, as demonstrated in the included example site. Otherwise, to enable math on the homepage or for all pages, you must globally set &lt;code&gt;math = true&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To disable source code highlighting by default for all pages, set &lt;code&gt;highlight = false&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt;. You can then enable source code highlighting only on pages that need it by setting &lt;code&gt;highlight = true&lt;/code&gt; in that page&amp;rsquo;s preamble. See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://TristanSalles.github.io/post/writing-markdown-latex/#code-highlighting&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;code-highlighting docs&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To display a featured image in content page headers, the parameters below can be inserted towards the end of a page&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;+++&lt;/code&gt; preamble. It is assumed that the image is located in your &lt;code&gt;static/img/&lt;/code&gt; folder, so the full path in the example below will be &lt;code&gt;static/img/headers/getting-started.png&lt;/code&gt;. The &lt;code&gt;caption&lt;/code&gt; parameter can be used to write an image caption or credit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-toml&#34;&gt;[header]
image = &amp;quot;headers/getting-started.png&amp;quot;
caption = &amp;quot;Image credit: [**Academic**](https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/)&amp;quot;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you wish to prevent a featured image automatically being used for a post&amp;rsquo;s thumbnail on the homepage, the &lt;code&gt;preview = false&lt;/code&gt; parameter can be added to &lt;code&gt;[header]&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;create-a-publication&#34;&gt;Create a publication&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create a new publication:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new publication/my-paper-name.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then edit the default variables at the top of &lt;code&gt;content/publication/my-paper-name.md&lt;/code&gt; to include the details of your publication. The &lt;code&gt;url_&lt;/code&gt; variables are used to generate links associated with your publication, such as for viewing PDFs of papers. Here is an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;+++
abstract = &amp;quot;An abstract...&amp;quot;
authors = [&amp;quot;First author&#39;s name&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Second author&#39;s name&amp;quot;]
date = &amp;quot;2013-07-01&amp;quot;
image = &amp;quot;&amp;quot;
image_preview = &amp;quot;&amp;quot;
math = false
publication = &amp;quot;The publishing part of the citation goes here. You may use *Markdown* for italics etc.&amp;quot;
title = &amp;quot;A publication title, such as title of a paper&amp;quot;
url_code = &amp;quot;&amp;quot;
url_dataset = &amp;quot;&amp;quot;
url_pdf = &amp;quot;pdf/my-paper-name.pdf&amp;quot;
url_project = &amp;quot;&amp;quot;
url_slides = &amp;quot;&amp;quot;
url_video = &amp;quot;&amp;quot;
+++

Further details on your publication can be written here using *Markdown* for formatting. This text will be displayed on the Publication Detail page.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;url_&lt;/code&gt; links can either point to local or web content. Associated local publication content, such as PDFs, may be copied to a &lt;code&gt;static/pdf/&lt;/code&gt; folder and referenced like &lt;code&gt;url_pdf = &amp;quot;pdf/my-paper-name.pdf&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also associate custom link buttons with the publication by adding the following block(s) within the variable preamble above, which is denoted by &lt;code&gt;+++&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[[url_custom]]
    name = &amp;quot;Custom Link&amp;quot;
    url = &amp;quot;http://www.example.org&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you enabled &lt;code&gt;detailed_list&lt;/code&gt; for publications in &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt;, then there are a few more optional variables that you can include in the publication page preamble. You may use &lt;code&gt;abstract_short = &amp;quot;friendly summary of abstract&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;publication_short = &amp;quot;abbreviated publication details&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; to display a friendly summary of the abstract and abbreviate the publication details, respectively. Furthermore, there is the option to display a different image on the homepage to the publication detail page by setting &lt;code&gt;image_preview = &amp;quot;my-image.jpg&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;. This can be useful if you wish to scale down the image for the homepage or simply if you just wish to show a different image for the preview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-warning&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Any double quotes (&lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;) or backslashes (e.g. LaTeX &lt;code&gt;\times&lt;/code&gt;) occurring within the value of any frontmatter parameter (such as the &lt;em&gt;abstract&lt;/em&gt;) should be escaped with a backslash (&lt;code&gt;\&lt;/code&gt;). For example, the symbol &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; and LaTeX text &lt;code&gt;\times&lt;/code&gt; become &lt;code&gt;\&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;\\times&lt;/code&gt;, respectively. Refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/toml-lang/toml#user-content-string&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TOML documentation&lt;/a&gt; for more info.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;post-an-article&#34;&gt;Post an article&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create a blog/news article:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new post/my-article-name.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then edit the newly created file &lt;code&gt;content/post/my-article-name.md&lt;/code&gt; with your full title and content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo will automatically generate summaries of posts that appear on the homepage. If you are dissatisfied with an automated summary, you can either limit the summary length by appropriately placing &lt;code&gt;&amp;#60;&amp;#33;&amp;#45;&amp;#45;more&amp;#45;&amp;#45;&amp;#62;&lt;/code&gt; in the article body, or completely override the automated summary by adding a &lt;code&gt;summary&lt;/code&gt; parameter to the &lt;code&gt;+++&lt;/code&gt; preamble such that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;summary = &amp;quot;Summary of my post.&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To disable commenting for a specific post, you can add &lt;code&gt;disable_comments = true&lt;/code&gt; to the post &lt;code&gt;+++&lt;/code&gt; preamble. Or to disable commenting for all posts, you can either set &lt;code&gt;disqusShortname = &amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;disable_comments = true&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;create-a-project&#34;&gt;Create a project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create a project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new project/my-project-name.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then edit the newly created file &lt;code&gt;content/project/my-project-name.md&lt;/code&gt;. Either you can link the project to an external project website by setting the &lt;code&gt;external_link = &amp;quot;http://external-project.com&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; variable at the top of the file, or you can add content (below the final &lt;code&gt;+++&lt;/code&gt;) in order to render a project page on your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;create-a-talk&#34;&gt;Create a talk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create a talk:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new talk/my-talk-name.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then edit the newly created file &lt;code&gt;content/talk/my-talk-name.md&lt;/code&gt; with your full talk title and details. Note that many of the talk parameters are similar to the publication parameters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;manage-node-index-pages&#34;&gt;Manage node index pages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The node index pages (e.g. &lt;code&gt;/post/&lt;/code&gt;) are the special pages which list all of your content. They can exist for blog posts, publications, and talks. The homepage widgets will automatically link to the node index pages when you have more items of content than can be displayed in the widget. Therefore, if you don&amp;rsquo;t have much content, you may not see the automatic links yet - but you can also manually link to them using a normal Markdown formatted link in your content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can edit the title and add your own content, such as an introduction, by creating and editing the following content files for the node indexes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new post/_index.md
hugo new publication/_index.md
hugo new talk/_index.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then remove all parameters except for &lt;code&gt;title&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;math&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;highlight&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;date&lt;/code&gt;. Edit the &lt;code&gt;title&lt;/code&gt; parameter as desired and add any content after the &lt;code&gt;+++&lt;/code&gt; preamble/frontmatter ends. For example, you should have something similar to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-toml&#34;&gt;+++
title = &amp;quot;List of my posts&amp;quot;
date = &amp;quot;2017-01-01T00:00:00Z&amp;quot;
math = false
highlight = false
+++

Below is an automatically generated list of all my blog posts!

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;removing-content&#34;&gt;Removing content&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, to remove content, simply delete the relevant file from your &lt;code&gt;content/post&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;content/publication&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;content/project&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;content/talk&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;view-your-updated-site&#34;&gt;View your updated site&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you have made changes to your site, you can view it by running the &lt;code&gt;hugo server --watch&lt;/code&gt; command and then opening &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;localhost:1313&lt;/a&gt; in your web browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;deploy-your-site&#34;&gt;Deploy your site&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, you can build the static website to a &lt;code&gt;public/&lt;/code&gt; folder ready for deployment using the &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may then deploy your site by copying the &lt;code&gt;public/&lt;/code&gt; directory (by FTP, SFTP, WebDAV, Rsync, git push, etc.) to your production web server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that running &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; does not remove any previously generated files before building. Therefore, it&amp;rsquo;s best practice to delete your &lt;code&gt;public/&lt;/code&gt; directory prior to running &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; to ensure no old or interim files are deployed to your server.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing content with Markdown, LaTeX, and Shortcodes</title>
      <link>https://TristanSalles.github.io/post/writing-markdown-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TristanSalles.github.io/post/writing-markdown-latex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Content can be written using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adam-p/markdown-here/wiki/Markdown-Cheatsheet&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/LaTeX/Mathematics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LaTeX math&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/extras/shortcodes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo Shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;. Additionally, HTML may be used for advanced formatting. This article gives an overview of the most common formatting options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sub-headings&#34;&gt;Sub-headings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## Heading 2
### Heading 3
#### Heading 4
##### Heading 5
###### Heading 6
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;emphasis&#34;&gt;Emphasis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Italics with *asterisks* or _underscores_.

Bold with **asterisks** or __underscores__.

Combined emphasis with **asterisks and _underscores_**.

Strikethrough with ~~two tildes~~.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ordered-lists&#34;&gt;Ordered lists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1. First item
2. Another item
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;unordered-lists&#34;&gt;Unordered lists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;* First item
* Another item
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;images&#34;&gt;Images&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Images may be added to a page by placing them in your &lt;code&gt;static/img/&lt;/code&gt; folder and referencing them using one of the following two notations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A general image:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;![alternative text for search engines](/img/screenshot.png)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A numbered figure with caption:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; figure src=&amp;quot;/img/screenshot.png&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Figure Caption&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[I&#39;m a link](https://www.google.com)
[A post]({{&amp;lt; ref &amp;quot;post/hi.md&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}})
[A publication]({{&amp;lt; ref &amp;quot;publication/hi.md&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}})
[A project]({{&amp;lt; ref &amp;quot;project/hi.md&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}})
[Another section]({{&amp;lt; relref &amp;quot;hi.md#who&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}})
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;emojis&#34;&gt;Emojis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webpagefx.com/tools/emoji-cheat-sheet/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Emoji cheat sheet&lt;/a&gt; for available emoticons. The following serves as an example, but you should remove the spaces between each emoji name and pair of semicolons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;I : heart : Academic : smile :
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ❤️ Academic 😄&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;blockquote&#34;&gt;Blockquote&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; This is a blockquote.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a blockquote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;I have more [^1] to say.

[^1]: Footnote example.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have more &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pass the &lt;em&gt;language&lt;/em&gt; of the code, such as &lt;code&gt;python&lt;/code&gt;, as a parameter after three backticks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;```python
# Example of code highlighting
input_string_var = input(&amp;quot;Enter some data: &amp;quot;)
print(&amp;quot;You entered: {}&amp;quot;.format(input_string_var))
```
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Result:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;# Example of code highlighting
input_string_var = input(&amp;quot;Enter some data: &amp;quot;)
print(&amp;quot;You entered: {}&amp;quot;.format(input_string_var))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;highlighting-options&#34;&gt;Highlighting options&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Academic theme uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://highlightjs.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;highlight.js&lt;/a&gt; for source code highlighting, and highlighting is enabled by default for all pages. However, several configuration options are supported that allow finer-grained control over highlight.js.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following table lists the supported options for configuring highlight.js, along with their expected type and a short description. A &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo; in the &lt;strong&gt;config.toml&lt;/strong&gt; column means the value can be set globally in &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt;, and a &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo; in the &lt;strong&gt;preamble&lt;/strong&gt; column means that the value can be set locally in a particular page&amp;rsquo;s preamble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;option&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;config.toml&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;preamble&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;highlight&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;boolean&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;enable/disable highlighting&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;highlight_languages&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;slice&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;choose additional languages&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;highlight_style&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;string&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;choose a highlighting style&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;highlight_version&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;string&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;choose the highlight.js version&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;option-highlight&#34;&gt;Option &lt;code&gt;highlight&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;highlight&lt;/code&gt; option allows enabling or disabling the inclusion of highlight.js, either globally or for a particular page. If the option is unset, it has the same effect as if you had specified &lt;code&gt;highlight = true&lt;/code&gt;. That is, the highlight.js javascript and css files will be included in every page. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to only include highlight.js files on pages that actually require source code highlighting, you can set &lt;code&gt;highlight = false&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt;, and then override it by setting &lt;code&gt;highlight = true&lt;/code&gt; in the preamble of any pages that require source code highlighting. Conversely, you could enable highlighting globally, and disable it locally for pages that do not require it. Here is a table that shows whether highlighting will be enabled for a page, based on the values of &lt;code&gt;highlight&lt;/code&gt; set in &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; and/or the page&amp;rsquo;s preamble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;config.toml&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;page preamble&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;highlighting enabled for page?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;unset or true&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;unset or true&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;unset or true&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;false&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;false&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;unset or false&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;false&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;true&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;option-highlight-languages&#34;&gt;Option &lt;code&gt;highlight_languages&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;highlight_languages&lt;/code&gt; option allows you to specify additional languages that are supported by highlight.js, but are not considered &amp;ldquo;common&amp;rdquo; and therefore are not supported by default. For example, if you want source code highlighting for Go and clojure in all pages, set &lt;code&gt;highlight_languages = [&amp;quot;go&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;clojure&amp;quot;]&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt;. If, on the other hand, you want to enable a language only for a specific page, you can set &lt;code&gt;highlight_languages&lt;/code&gt; in that page&amp;rsquo;s preamble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;highlight_languages&lt;/code&gt; options specified in &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; and in a page&amp;rsquo;s preamble are additive. That is, if &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; contains, &lt;code&gt;highlight_languages = [&amp;quot;go&amp;quot;]&lt;/code&gt; and the page&amp;rsquo;s preamble contains &lt;code&gt;highlight_languages = [&amp;quot;ocaml&amp;quot;]&lt;/code&gt;, then javascript files for &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; go and ocaml will be included for that page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the &lt;code&gt;highlight_languages&lt;/code&gt; option is set, then the corresponding javascript files will be served from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cdnjs.com/libraries/highlight.js/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;cdnjs server&lt;/a&gt;. To see a list of available languages, visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cdnjs.com/libraries/highlight.js/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;cdnjs page&lt;/a&gt; and search for links with the word &amp;ldquo;languages&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;highlight_languages&lt;/code&gt; option provides an easy and convenient way to include support for additional languages to be severed from a CDN. If serving unmodified files from cdnjs doesn&amp;rsquo;t meet your needs, you can include javascript files for additional language support via one of the methods described in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://TristanSalles.github.io/post/getting-started/#third-party-and-local-scripts-js&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;getting started guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;option-highlight-style&#34;&gt;Option &lt;code&gt;highlight_style&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;highlight_style&lt;/code&gt; option allows you to select an alternate css style for highlighted code. For example, if you wanted to use the solarized-dark style, you could set &lt;code&gt;highlight_style = &amp;quot;solarized-dark&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the &lt;code&gt;highlight_style&lt;/code&gt; option is unset, the default is to use the file &lt;code&gt;/css/highlight.min.css&lt;/code&gt;, either the one provided by the Academic theme, or else the one in your local &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt; directory.  The &lt;code&gt;/css/highlight.min.css&lt;/code&gt; file provided by Academic is equivalent to the &lt;code&gt;github&lt;/code&gt; style from highlight.js.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the &lt;code&gt;highlight_style&lt;/code&gt; option &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; set, then &lt;code&gt;/css/highlight.min.css&lt;/code&gt; is ignored, and the corresponding css file will be served from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cdnjs.com/libraries/highlight.js/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;cdnjs server&lt;/a&gt;. To see a list of available styles, visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cdnjs.com/libraries/highlight.js/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;cdnjs page&lt;/a&gt; and search for links with the word &amp;ldquo;styles&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://highlightjs.org/static/demo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;highlight.js demo page&lt;/a&gt; for examples of available styles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Not all styles listed on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://highlightjs.org/static/demo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;highlight.js demo page&lt;/a&gt; are available from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cdnjs.com/libraries/highlight.js/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;cdnjs server&lt;/a&gt;. If you want to use a style that is not served by cdnjs, just leave &lt;code&gt;highlight_style&lt;/code&gt; unset, and place the corresponding css file in &lt;code&gt;/static/css/highlight.min.css&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t want to change the default style that ships with Academic but you do want the style file served from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cdnjs.com/libraries/highlight.js/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;cdnjs server&lt;/a&gt;, set &lt;code&gt;highlight_style = &amp;quot;github&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;highlight_style&lt;/code&gt; option is only recognized when set in &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt;. Setting &lt;code&gt;highlight_style&lt;/code&gt; in your page&amp;rsquo;s preamble has no effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;option-highlight-version&#34;&gt;Option &lt;code&gt;highlight_version&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;highlight_version&lt;/code&gt; option, as the name implies, allows you to select the version of highlight.js you want to use. The default value is &amp;ldquo;9.9.0&amp;rdquo;. The &lt;code&gt;highlight_version&lt;/code&gt; option is only recognized when set in &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt;. Setting &lt;code&gt;highlight_version&lt;/code&gt; in your page&amp;rsquo;s preamble has no effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;Twitter tweet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To include a single tweet, pass the tweet’s ID from the tweet&amp;rsquo;s URL as parameter to the shortcode:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; tweet 666616452582129664 &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;youtube&#34;&gt;Youtube&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; youtube w7Ft2ymGmfc &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;vimeo&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; vimeo 146022717 &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;github-gist&#34;&gt;GitHub gist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; gist USERNAME GIST-ID  &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-deck&#34;&gt;Speaker Deck&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; speakerdeck 4e8126e72d853c0060001f97 &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rm-latex-math&#34;&gt;$\rm \LaTeX$ math&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-TeX&#34;&gt;$$\left [ – \frac{\hbar^2}{2 m} \frac{\partial^2}{\partial x^2} + V \right ] \Psi = i \hbar \frac{\partial}{\partial t} \Psi$$
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$\left [ – \frac{\hbar^2}{2 m} \frac{\partial^2}{\partial x^2} + V \right ] \Psi = i \hbar \frac{\partial}{\partial t} \Psi$$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, inline math can be written by wrapping the formula with only a single &lt;code&gt;$&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This is inline: $\mathbf{y} = \mathbf{X}\boldsymbol\beta + \boldsymbol\varepsilon$
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is inline: $\mathbf{y} = \mathbf{X}\boldsymbol\beta + \boldsymbol\varepsilon$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;table&#34;&gt;Table&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Markdown&#34;&gt;| Command           | Description                    |
| ------------------| ------------------------------ |
| `hugo`            | Build your website.            |
| `hugo serve -w`   | View your website.             |
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Result:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Command&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Build your website.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo serve -w&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;View your website.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;alerts&#34;&gt;Alerts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alerts are a useful feature that add side content such as tips, notes, or warnings to your articles. They are especially handy when writing educational tutorial-style articles. Use the corresponding shortcodes to enable alerts inside your content:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{% alert note %}}
Here&#39;s a tip or note...
{{% /alert %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will display the following &lt;em&gt;note&lt;/em&gt; block:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a tip or note&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{% alert warning %}}
Here&#39;s some important information...
{{% /alert %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will display the following &lt;em&gt;warning&lt;/em&gt; block:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-warning&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s some important information&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;Footnote example.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Badlands: An open-source, flexible and parallel framework to study landscape dynamics</title>
      <link>https://TristanSalles.github.io/publication/compgeo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TristanSalles.github.io/publication/compgeo/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geomorphology</title>
      <link>https://TristanSalles.github.io/project/deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TristanSalles.github.io/project/deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zenodo.org/badge/latestdoi/51286954&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://zenodo.org/badge/51286954.svg&#34; alt=&#34;DOI&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ba&lt;/strong&gt;sin an&lt;strong&gt;d&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Lan&lt;/strong&gt;dscape &lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;ynamic&lt;strong&gt;s&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;Badlands&lt;/strong&gt;) is a parallel TIN-based landscape evolution model, built to simulate topography development at various space and time scales. The model is capable of simulating hillslope processes (&lt;strong&gt;linear&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;strong&gt;non-linear&lt;/strong&gt; diffusion), fluvial incision (&lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;modified&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Stream Power Law&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Transport Capacity Law&lt;/strong&gt; both for sediment  erosion/transport/deposition), spatially and temporally varying geodynamic (horizontal + vertical displacements) and climatic forces which can be used to simulate changes in base level, as well as effects of climate changes or sea-level fluctuations. The model uses  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/awickert/gFlex&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gFlex&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; package which is designed to solve elastic plate flexure for applications to Earth&amp;rsquo;s lithosphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://prezi.com/5y1usorz8e8k/badlands-overview/?utm_campaign=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=copy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Badlands overview&lt;/a&gt; - Basin Genesis Hub presentation (2017)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting started&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For installation information and documentation visit our github &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/badlands-model/pyBadlands/wiki&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wiki page&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; which provides several useful notes on how to start using the tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to get started is with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/u/badlandsmodel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Docker container&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/kitematic/userguide/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kitematic&lt;/a&gt;. Once &lt;strong&gt;Kitematic&lt;/strong&gt; is installed on your computer, open it and look for &lt;strong&gt;pybadlands-demo&lt;/strong&gt; via the &lt;em&gt;search&lt;/em&gt; menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to install it yourself, these 2 Dockerfiles (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/badlands-model/pyBadlands-Dependencies-Docker/blob/master/Dockerfile&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dependencies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/badlands-model/pyBadlands-Docker-Demo/blob/master/Dockerfile&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;code&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) are the best documentation of the required packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest pyBadlands version is the one that’s in our Github &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/badlands-model/pyBadlands&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;repository&lt;/a&gt;. Get it using this shell command, which requires Git:
- &lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/badlands-model/pyBadlands.git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API documentation&lt;/strong&gt; is available from &lt;a href=&#34;http://pybadlands.readthedocs.io/en/master/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://pybadlands.readthedocs.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-specs&#34;&gt;The specs&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The model is based on the following characteristics:
+ The finite volume approach from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0098300400001345&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tucker et al. (2001)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; based on the dual Delaunay-Voronoi framework is used to solve the continuity equation explicitly,
+ Node ordering is perform efficiently based on the work from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0169555X12004618&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Braun &amp;amp; Willett (2013)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,
+ 3D surface deformations using the node refinement technique proposed by &lt;a href=&#34;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/2014GC005490/abstract;jsessionid=48A885F79A40B1E3E76AFC1BEAA2B238.f03t03&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thieulot et al. ( 2014)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
+ Orographic precipitation using &lt;a href=&#34;http://journals.ametsoc.org/doi/abs/10.1175/1520-0469(2004)061%3C1377%3AALTOOP%3E2.0.CO%3B2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smith &amp;amp; Barstad (2004)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; linear model to compute topographic induced rain field.
+ Varying erodibility layers (both horizontally and vertically) to simulate impact of changing sediment characteristics on landscape evolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A set of functions for &lt;em&gt;pre&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;post&lt;/em&gt;-processing of &lt;strong&gt;Badlands&lt;/strong&gt; inputs and outputs is available in a GitHub &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/badlands-model/pyBadlands-Companion&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Companion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; repository which is already shipped with the Badlands Docker container.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;community-driven&#34;&gt;Community driven&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public License as published by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU Lesser General Public License for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public License along with this program.  If not, see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/lgpl-3.0.en.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/lgpl-3.0.en.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;versioning&#34;&gt;Versioning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current releases (&lt;strong&gt;DOI&lt;/strong&gt; citable):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Release v1.0.0 :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.160412&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Release 1: badlands-model/pyBadlands&lt;/a&gt;, Zenodo, doi:10.5281/zenodo.160412, 2016.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Release v1.1.0 :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.268053&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Release 2: badlands-model/pyBadlands&lt;/a&gt;, Zenodo, doi:10.5281/zenodo.268053, 2017.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;v2.0.0 Release Candidate :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch is a stable version of the code with the most recent developments embedded and is expected to be released as &lt;strong&gt;version 2.0.0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;reporting&#34;&gt;Reporting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you come accross a bug or if you need some help compiling or using the code you can:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;go through our mailing list &lt;a href=&#34;http://mailman.sydney.edu.au/pipermail/badlands/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;subscribe to our &lt;a href=&#34;http://mailman.sydney.edu.au/mailman/listinfo/badlands&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;or &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:badlands@mailman.sydney.edu.au&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;drop us a line&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hands-on-examples&#34;&gt;Hands-on examples&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A compilation of notebooks with examples are proposed to give you a quick feeling of what could be done with the code. Testing models:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;delta evolution under sea-level fluctuation &lt;a href=&#34;http://nbviewer.jupyter.org/github/badlands-model/pyBadlands/blob/master/Examples/delta/delta.ipynb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;nbviewer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;impact of climate on mountain dynamic &lt;a href=&#34;http://nbviewer.jupyter.org/github/badlands-model/pyBadlands/blob/master/Examples/mountain/mountain.ipynb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;nbviewer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;basin filling associated to a strike-slip fault system &lt;a href=&#34;http://nbviewer.jupyter.org/github/badlands-model/pyBadlands/blob/master/Examples/strikeslip/strike-slip.ipynb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;nbviewer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;infilling of a crater-type topography &lt;a href=&#34;http://nbviewer.jupyter.org/github/badlands-model/pyBadlands/blob/master/Examples/crater/crater.ipynb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;nbviewer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;flexural response due to loading and unloading under variable elastic thickness &lt;a href=&#34;http://nbviewer.jupyter.org/github/badlands-model/pyBadlands/blob/master/Examples/flexure/flexure.ipynb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;nbviewer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;quick setup of real topography/bathymetry model using etopo1 &lt;a href=&#34;http://nbviewer.jupyter.org/github/badlands-model/pyBadlands/blob/master/Examples/etopo/etopo.ipynb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;nbviewer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numerical modelling of tectonically driven river dynamics and deposition in an upland incised valley</title>
      <link>https://TristanSalles.github.io/publication/geomorph/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TristanSalles.github.io/publication/geomorph/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
